Guide to the Danbury Miscellanea Collection MS 038
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Realia and Publications
  - Greater Danbury Business Digest, 1985-1995 (with gaps) (Box 4)
    March: topics include Gillotte, balloons etc., Loree's Kitchen, Catering, Durant's, Mall PartyApril: Century 21, John Ashkar, Ethan Allen, Maguire, Dalessio, NeJame and Sons, Dr. Headley, Judge Geen, Bedoukian, weight watchers
    May: topics include John Hyattt Associates, Snet, Century business machines, Computer Cabling, Nelson's, Compulearn, softown, Joseph Merritt
    June: topics include Eugene Brennan, Holman Inc., William Pitt, Pre-Engineered Building, J.L. Beers, Silvestri Fencing, D'Agostino's, Balloon Hollow
    July: topics include Dolan Family, Bethel and the Dolans, Bethel, Clarke Industrial Park, Consolidated Controls, Pawloski Lumber, Stoney Hill, Southbury 200 August: Cunis and Nolan, University Center, Abbott Tech September: Geoffrey Ball, Benedict's, The Arch, Stroble Banking, La Fortuna, Pasta Fresca, 1848 House
    October: topics include Sylvester Craig, Ambassador Express, Heart, Gilbert and Bennett, Heibeck's, Georgetown, Cannondale, United Way November: topics include Bob Sharp, Belardinelli, Brady-Stannard, Super Sunday Rally, Watertown Auto Mall, Stevenson's, Pamby Motors, Junior Achievement
    December: topics include Alice Voltaire, Kent, Kimberly of Connecticut, Krutolow, Adar Pewter, Kent Carved Signs
    1988
    January: topics include John Creasy, Danbury Hospital, Sports Vision, Woodbury Ski & Racquet, McAffrey and Booth, Bethel Veterinary
    February: topics include Greater Danbury economy, New Milford Hospital, Carl Epple, Ancell School WCSU, March: SCORE, Cellular phones, chimney sweeps, collectibles, Hilton
    May: topics include Tom Nash, Acorn Press, Loebei Productions, G.V. M., Grolier, Putnam Photo, USA direct
    June: topics include Mark Nolan, Nolan Enterprises, Good Fellows, Sandy Hook, Bruce Campell Graham, Lee Farm, Backhoe Jack, Barden, Morgan Horses
    July: topics include Carl Borodenko, Brookfield Market, Bicentennial, The Bike Shop, Brookfield, Wentworth Labs August: Lucy Wilson, Women in business, Pepperidge Farm, Labor Crunch, Joyce Ligi, Church Street Trading, Waterbury's Rennaissance
    September: topics include The Inn at Ridgefield, Johannes Brugger, Rainer Kuhnt, Capriccio, B&C Smith, Rudy's, Edelweiss
    October: topics include Joseph Kehoe, Prudential-Bache, Davis and Hoyt, Affordable Housing, Southbury, Connecticut National Bank
    November: topics include Charles Orrs, New Milford VW, Georgetown Motors, Car Land, Humphrey & Sons, Kennedy and Crew, United Way, Peat Marwick
    December: topics include Gio Digilio and Dan Dayton, G. Daniels, Palo Imports, Copps Hill, Cappiello Jewlers, Emily's, Southwest Charcuterie
    1989
    January: topics include Greater Naubmer #1, Ives Center, Novo Labs February: topics include Paul Hancock, New Milford Cablevision, Goodwick Associates, Topstone Industries, Koenigs Art Emporium, WFAR March: topics include Fax Fever, GSI Development Company, Contact Systems, Lee F. Witter, Computer Software, Sherman Furniture
    April: topics include A.J. and Allyson J. Bernard, RE/MAX, gallery vendome, Danbury Personal Counseling, Iron Artist, Ed's Bait
    May: topics include YMCA, Gary Kozak, Bike Express, Consolidated Controls
    June: topics include Anthony Rizzo, Wired for Success, Novella, Bethel Company, IRCA, Bauer Fence, Smith Brothers, L & J Pools, Apex Glass, Morganti, North Street Hardware
    July: topics include Ridgefield, Dick Venus, Stepping Stone Farm August: topics include Charter Personel, Louise Fornabaio, Tom Fornabaio, Newtown Real Estate
    September: topics include John Matos, Pancho and Gringo's, Blue Grotto, Rosie Tomorrow's, Tauton Tavern, Bountiful Board, Fairfield Restaurant Supply, Barbara Volz, Brewster Ford, Danbury Auto Spring, Ridgefield European Motors, Secundi's Truck Shop, Hawk Trucking, CD 1 stop November: topics include Ross and Beverly Nichols, Ski Haus, Downtown Danbury, Restaurant Row, Maxine Furs, Gordon Frasier, Natural Merchant December: topics include A Searle Pinney, Bobby Payne, Pinney Payne Van Lenten Burell Wolfe and Dillman, PC, AG Edwards, Liberty National Bank, Reynolds and Rowella
    1990
    January: topics include Danbury Economy, Cathy Glazer, mailboxes etc February: topics include Taunton Press, Jan Wahlin, John Kelsey, John Lively, Ethan Allen Communications, Grolier
    March: topics include Michael Marcus, Marcus Dairy, Voicemail round-up, New England Energy Management, Superior Office Supplies
    May: topics include Brookfield FAmily Medicine, Geron Nursing
    June: topics include Anna and Gary Seaman, Seaman Lynch hardware, Blansfield Builders, Eppoliti, New Milford Block and Supply, Jim Broaddus, Cabinetmaker, one-to-one fitness, Ferris Farm
    July: topics include Anniversary issue, Ives Center, Candlewood National Bank
    August: topics include Highborn Horse Park, Southbury and Woodbury, Datahr Employment Services
    September: topics include Carol Peck, Capers, Sushi Yoshi, The Main Brace, Suzanah's, Stonehenge Restaurant
    October: topics include Black Swan, Westside Cruise, Nutmeg Plumbing Supply, Kingswood Kitchens, Matz Lumber, Hayes Chevrolet, Rapid Lube, Maaco
    November: topics include Danbury Mall, Woodbury Pewterers, Focus on Brewster, NY
    December: topics include Payne Nursery, Recycling, Bailey Financial, Health Benefits Round-up, Robert Preston
    1991
    January: topics include Danbury economy, Jim Silvestri, Frank Mariano, John J. Allen, Hank Zinccara, Richard Jabara
    February: topics include Weddings
    March: topics include Ergonomics, interTech, BKAM, outplacement
    May: topics include Pronto Aire, Laura Donnelly, Danbury Hospital, CareProgram
    June: topics include Thomas Schwenke, Engelhard and Koenig, Clark Construction, New England Glass Enclosures, Old Town Barns, Fred Dill July: topics include Bob Goodfellow, Goodfellow-Ashmore, Mayor Eriquez, Geno Arconti, Danbury Industrial
    September: topics include Richard Jabara, Motel Associates, Ernie's Roadhouse, Maison le Blanc, Inn Keepers, Jim Barbaries, players/Gold's gym
    October: topics include Jim Hetherington, Fair Auto Park, Wilson-Thiney Design, Cal Brunen, Connecticut Bomanite
    July: topics include Professional Water Systems, Jay Brundage, American Environmental technologies, Professional Water Systems, WLAD radio August: topics include The childcare Round-up, Town of Bethel
    December: topics include Edward Baruch, Cutsumpas, Collins, Ancona Sports, Diversified Group Brokerage, First night Danbury, Duty Free International
    1992
    January: topics include Wedding Issue, bridal showcase, Fox Hill Inn Brookfield
    February: topics include Small business guide, S.C.O.R.E, zoning
    March: topics include LORAD, Davis and Geck, Prep Schools, Tony Pellegrino, Medical Manufacturers April: Robert Noce, Noce Associates Home buyers guide
    May: topics include Balloon Hollow, Paul and Valerie Morlock, Coach Tours, Traveler's Guide
    June: topics include Ethan Allen, Farooq Kathwari, Caldwell Walsh, Martere's
    July: topics include New Milford Hospital
    August: topics include United Way, D'ART, Super Merchandisers, CityCenter update, Mayor Gene Eriquez
    September: topics include Bella Italia, Sesame Seed, Sam's Grill, Dining Out Guide
    October: topics include John Val Tires, Julien Val, Waterworks, Danubry Audi-Porsche, McCaffery and Booth, Danbury Auto Appearance November: topics include Beaux Visages, Time After Time, Welcome to Newtown, Judy Volpe
    December: topics include Larry Hoyt, AJ Carnall, Cramer and Anderson, area college directory
    1993
    January: topics include Wedding issue February: economics review, Pamby Motors, Sirianni Mortgage
    March: topics include Roger Littlejohn, First Brands Corporation, Skip Barber
    April: topics include Paul Scalzo Modular Homes, Wlecome to Geater Danbury, boarding Schools
    June: topics include Dobson pools, Hollandia Nurseries, Kitchens Plus, outdoor environments
    July/August: topics include Jim Williams, Walter G. Southworth Inc., New Milford homebuyers guide, Ancell School of Business
    September: topics include The Mayflower Inn, Robert Mnuchin, Ariana Mnuchin, Stew Leonard's, Bon Apetit, Main Moon, CityCenter, Great chefs October: topics include Pamby Motors, Michael Pambianchi, Ridgefield clubs and organizations, buy american
    November: topics include Carole Joy Creations, Victor and Carole Gellineao, All things Newtown
    December: topics include Robert Levy, T.R. Paul, Home Healthcare, education
    1994
    January: topcis include wedding issue, Tollgate Hill Inn, Homewood Doves, Dawn's Pizzazz, Queen of Hearts, J&B Band
    February: topcis include Economic Review, Baker, Moots & Pellegrini PC, TQM (total quality management),
    March: topics include Ryer Associates, Super Banks, William Riebe, Riebe and Sons Construction, Welcome to Bethel, home construction April: topics include Wooster School, Welcome to Danbury
    May: topics include Ruiter's Coachworks, Richard and Robert Ruiter, Mountain Workshop, Local wineries, teambuilding in the wilderness, local vineyards
    June: topics include elder care, hancock hall, Barbara Malone, Frank Malone, traveler's guide
    July: topics include New Milford Bank and Trust Company, Michael Carrigan, Bank Presidents, New Milford buyers guide
    August: topics include Retooling the MBA, Modern offices
    September: topics include Restaurant guide, Le Chateau restaurant Francais, Joseph Jaffre, Monique Jaffre, Fiddler's restaurant, savory Fare Soups, Carol Peck's Good News Cafe
    October: topics include Ridgefield, anatoly Gelvasser, angel international, video matchmaking, liberated executives
    November: topics include Eastcoast music mall, Welcome to Newtown December: topics include Robotics, Joseph Engel, Security industry
    1995
    February: topics include Werner Gerstenberg, boehringer Ingleheim Corporation, Danbury's economic future, Hawley Real Estate
    March: topics include chemical marketing concepts, David Begin, Deborah Pritchard, Attorneys, fast growing companies
    April: topics include Richard Jabara, Motel associates, rampart group, business travelers guide
    May: topics include Berkshire Corporate Park, Richard Steiner, Duracell construction, franchising, commercial real estate
    June: topics include 10th anniversary issue, leaders of tomorrow, super merchandisers, Class A office space.
  - Scrap book - "Flood 10-15-55", 1955; 26867 (Box OS 1, Folder 1)
    12" x 14" scrapbook. Contains snapshots of downtown Danbury during flood and newspaper clippings from the Danbury News Times (w/ photocopy of clippings).
  - Danbury American Revolution Bicentennial Commemorative Coins, 1977 (Box OS 1)
    20 coins
  - Danbury Traffic Survey (facsimile), 1939 (Box OS 1)
  - WCSU Sandy Hook Tribute Realia, December, 19, 2012 (Box OS 1)
    1 Crystal Rock water bottle, 1 battery powered candle, 1 long stem yellow rose
  - Miscellaneous elementry education booklets, etc., 1889-1930; 59012 (Box OS 1, Folder *)
    Includes: Ve-po-ad (adding machine); Advanced System for Locating Errors (1894); Arithmetical Detector (1894); Decimplex Improvement (1897); Catholic National Reader: New Primer (1893). Gift of the Longridge Library.
  - City of Danbury, "Mayor's Proclamation: National Drunk and Drugged Driving (3D) Prevention Month," December 8, 1993, 26107 (Box OS 1, Folder *)
  - Don't "Walk on By"…creating a sculpture trail so we won't miss notable outdoor sculpture in our midst by the Woman's Club of Danbury/ New Fairfield, Inc., 2002-2004; 26143 (Box OS 1, Folder *)
  - Economic Evaluation of Candlewood Lake, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Congregational Church Sermon given by Rev. Samuel G. Coe, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Event Programs, 1969-1988 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    Ives Centennial Concert Flyer, 1988 Ives Centennial Concert Brochure, 1988 Ives Centennital Concert Brochure, 1974 American Flag Program Brochure, 1969
- Cookbooks and Menus
  - Danbury Restaurant Menus, 1936; 26149 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    Hotel Green, Christmas menu, 1936 Shanley's, menu
  - Mama Lariccia's Famous El Dorado, Lido Room. 152-54 West St. Danbury - Menu, ca. 1959; 54710 (Box OS 1, Folder 2)
    Gift of the Robert H. Krejci Trust, 2012
  - The Bicentennial Cookbook: Ethnic Recipes from Danbury Area, 1974 (Box 5, Item 1)
    Compiled by the American Revolution Bicentennial Stearing Committee, Danbury, Connecticut.
  - Danbury Multicultural Cookbook, circa 2000s (Box 5, Item 2)
    Published by Danbury Children First
  - Treasured Recipes, 1995 (Box 5, Item 3)
    Published by the Shelter Rocks School
  - A Gardener Cooks, 1996 (Box 5, Item 4)
    Published by the Danbury Garden Club
  - The Danbury New-Fairfield Newcomers Club Cookbook, 1980s (Box 5, Item 5)
  - D.A.Y.O. Family Cookbook, 1995 (Box 5, Item 6)
  - King Street United Church of Christ Cookbook, 1994 (Box 5, Item 7)
  - International Recipes From Students, Tutors, and Friends of Literacy Volunteers of America-Danbury, 1993 (Box 5, Item 8)
    Published by the Literacy Volunteers of America
  - Danbury Creamery Cookbook, circa 1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    A cookbook for the economical housewife. Published by the Frederick Matthew's Company.